Register of the Alfred M. Lilienthal papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Alfred M. Lilienthal papers
1936-1999
82070
Hoover Institution Archives
260 manuscript boxes, 2 cubic foot boxes, 9 oversize boxes, 1 card file box, 189 envelopes, 2 motion picture film reels (129.2 linear feet)
Speeches and writings, correspondence, notes, memoranda, press releases, serial issues, conference papers, interviews, studies, clippings, other printed matter, photographs, motion picture film, and sound recordings relating to the Middle East, Arab-Israeli relations, and American foreign policy in the region. Also available on microfilm (157 reels).
Lilienthal, Alfred M.
Access
Collection is open for research.
Use copies of some sound recordings and motion picture film in this collection are available for immediate access. To listen to other sound recordings or to view videos during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1982.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Alternative Form Available
Also available on microfilm (157 reels).
Biographical Note
1913 December 25 Born, New York City
1934 B.A. Cornell University
1938 LL.B. Columbia University Admitted to New York Bar
1939-1941 With Bennet, House and Counts, New York City
1940 President, Republican First Voters League
1941 Fusion party candidate for New York City Counci; actively opposed American Youth Congress
1942-43, 1945-48 With the State Department, Division of Defense Materials
1943-1945 Served with the U.S. Army in the Middle East
1945 Consultant to the U.S. Delegation at the United Nations Conference on International Organization, San Francisco
1947-1950 In administrative practice
1947-1952 Counsel, American Council for Judaism, Washington Chapter
1949-1950 Secretary, Holyland Emergency Liaison Program, Inc. (H.E.L.P.)
1951- Lecturer; TV and radio commentator; author of magazine articles and syndicated newspieces; frequent traveller to the Middle East
1953 Author, What Price Israel?
1956 Founder and chairman, National Committee for Security and Justice in the Middle East
1957 Author, There Goes the Middle East
1958 April-August Middle East columnist, Nashville Banner (Tennessee) and Arizona Daily Star
1958-1959 Assistant photographer and editor, 16mm documentary color film "The Turbulent Middle East," for lecture use, 1959-1973
1960-1965 Founder and counsel, American Arab Association for Commerce and Industry
1965 Author, The Other Side of the Coin
1968-1985 Editor and publisher of the monthly newsletter Middle East Perspective
1969 J.D. Columbia University
1976-1977 Political columnist, daily Al Qabas, Kuwait
1978 Author, The Zionist Connection
2008 October 6 Died, Washington, D.C.
Scope and Content of Collection
Speeches and writings, correspondence, notes, memoranda, press releases, serial issues, conference papers, interviews, studies, clippings, other printed matter, photographs, motion picture film, and sound recordings relating to the Middle East, Arab-Israeli relations, and American foreign policy in the region.
Middle East Perspective.; Jewish-Arab relations.; Zionism.; Israel.; Middle East--Foreign relations--United States.; Middle East.; United States--Foreign relations--Middle East.; Journalists.; Audiotapes.; Video tapes.; Motion pictures.
- BIOGRAPHICAL FILE, 1940-1995 (Boxes 1-8, 152-153)
  Scope and Contents note
  Appointment calendars, articles, bibliographies, biographies, conversation transcripts, correspondence, research files, schedules, clippings, and other printed matter, arranged alphabetically by physical form.
  - Addresses (Box-folder 1: 1)
  - Appointment calendars and schedules, 1956-1985 (Box-folder 1: 2)
  - Articles on Alfred M. Lilienthal (hereafter AML), 1957-1982 (Box-folder 1: 3)
  - Bibliographies (Box-folder 1: 4)
  - Biographical data (Box-folder 1: 5)
  - Biographies (Box-folder 1: 6)
  - Clippings and other printed matter mentioning AML (publicity file) (Box-folder 1: 7)
    Includes some correspondence, in particular regarding radio or television appearances, undated or in Arabic.
    - 1940-1956 (Box-folder 1: 8-14)
    - 1957-1977 (Box-folder 2: 1-16)
    - 1978-1988 (Box-folder 3: 1-11)
    - 1989 (Box-folder 152: 23)
    - 1990- (Box-folder 152: 36)
  - Comments on AML (Box-folder 3: 12)
  - Conversation transcripts (Box-folder 3: 13)
  - Fan mail
    - General (Box-folder 3: 14)
    - 1967 (Box-folder 3: 15)
    - 1971 (Box-folder 3: 16)
    - 1974 (Box-folder 3: 17)
    - 1975-1981 (Box-folder 4: 1-5)
    - 1981-1985 (Box-folder 5: 1-5)
  - Freedom of Information Act request, 1991 (Box-folder 152: 40)
    Correspondence with the State Department and released photocopies of reports on AML, 1960-1988.
  - Hate mail (Box-folder 5: 6-7)
  - Job review, 1943 (Box-folder 6: 1)
  - Letters of note (Box-folder 6: 2)
  - Miscellaneous (Box-folder 6: 3)
  - Printed matter (reprints of speeches, publicity brochures, etc.) (Box-folder 6: 4)
  - Research file (Box-folder 6: 5-7)
  - Research files (Box-folder 7: 1-7)
  - Sketch of AML by Prince Mohamed bin Saud (Box-folder 7: 8)
  - Subject file
    - Ad placed in the New York Times, 1958 (Box-folder 7: 9)
    - Charitable contributions (Box-folder 7: 10)
    - Excommunication by the Supreme Rabbinic Court of America, 1982 (Box-folder 7: 11)
    - Family (Box-folder 152: 41)
    - Libel suits
      - Raphael, G. (Box-folder 8: 1)
      - Giesen, Edna (Box-folder 8: 2)
    - Lilienthal 40th Anniversary Fund (Box-folder 152: 4)
    - "Middle East Caravan" (Box-folder 8: 3)
      Brochures, itineraries, and correspondence of a trip that AML planned for the beginning of 1958 (eventually canceled).
    - Points of controversy (Box-folder 8: 4)
    - Public relations [See also: CORRESPONDENCE, Kuwait. Ministry of Foreign Affairs]
      - General (Box-folder 8: 5-7)
      - Baldwin, Donald (Box-folder 8: 8)
      - Denton, Dorothy (Box-folder 8: 9)
      - Dorney, C. Kelly (Box-folder 8: 10)
      - Eaton, Louise (Box-folder 8: 11)
      - Keedick, Robert (Box-folder 8: 12)
      - Lynch, Ware (Box-folder 8: 13)
      - Wade, Clint (Box-folder 8: 14)
    - Questions to be asked of AML when interviewed by the media (Box-folder 8: 15)
    - U.S. Army service (Box-folder 8: 16)
    - United Nations Organization (Box-folder 153: 27)
      Material relating to the San Francisco UN50 Charter Commemorative Ceremony, San Francisco, California, 26 June 1995, which AML attended. Includes a photocopy of a clipping relating to his participation in the 1945 Conference and of his admission ticket.
  - Tributes in the form of letters and telegrams upon AML's 80th birthday celebration and 40th anniversary of What Price Israel? University Club, Washington, D.C., 1993 December 18 (Box-folder 153: 12)
    Includes 1994 correspondence.
- CORRESPONDENCE, 1936-1994 (Boxes 9-30, 152-153)
  Arranged alphabetically by name of correspondent.
  - General
    - Telegrams, 1973-1984 (Box-folder 9: 1-3)
    - 1945-1981 (Box-folder 9: 4-12)
    - 1954-1968 (Box-folder 10: 1-11)
    - 1969-1972 (Box-folder 11: 1-14)
    - 1979 February - 1980 February (Box-folder 12: 1-8)
    - 1980 February - 1981 March (Box-folder 13: 1-9)
    - 1981 March-December (Box-folder 14: 1-10)
    - 1982 January-August (Box-folder 15: 1-8)
    - 1982 September - 1983 June (Box-folder 16: 1-10)
    - 1983 July - 1984 November (Box-folder 17: 1-12)
  - Aamiry, Muhammad, 1970-1971 (Box-folder 18: 1)
  - Abaza, Ibrahim, 1970-1976 (Box-folder 18: 2)
  - Abourezk, James, 1973-1980 (Box-folder 18: 3)
  - Abukishk, Saud S., 1968-1969 (Box-folder 18: 4)
  - Acheson, Dean, 1968-1969 (Box-folder 18: 5)
  - Ad Hoc Committee on the Middle East, 1968 (Box-folder 18: 6)
  - Adler, Frank J., 1977-1978 (Box-folder 18: 7)
  - Agnew, Spiro, 1969-1978 (Box-folder 18: 8)
  - Ahmed, S. S., 1968-1977 (Box-folder 18: 9)
  - Aiken, George D., 1969 (Box-folder 18: 10)
  - Ajami, Fawad, 1978 (Box-folder 18: 11)
  - Akins, James E., 1973 (Box-folder 18: 12)
  - Albertson, Jim, 1961 (Box-folder 18: 13)
  - Algeria. Ministry of Foreign Affairs, 1971 (Box-folder 18: 14)
  - Algeria. Permanent Mission to the United Nations, 1977-1982 (Box-folder 18: 15)
  - Ali, Muhammad, 1968-1977 (Box-folder 18: 16)
  - Ali, Wijdan, 1979-1984 (Box-folder 18: 17)
  - Alia Airlines, 1983-1984 (Box-folder 18: 18)
  - Allan, Douglas, 1960-1961 (Box-folder 18: 19)
  - Allen, Richard V., 1968-1981 (Box-folder 18: 20)
  - American-Arab Affairs Council (George A. Naifeh), 1984 (Box-folder 18: 21)
  - American Broadcasting Company
    - General, 1956-1980 (Box-folder 18: 22)
    - Re "Directions" programs of 5 March and 2 April 1978 (Box-folder 18: 23)
  - American Committee for Cultural Freedom [See: National Broadcasting Company]
  - American Committee for Justice in the Middle East, 1970-1972 (Box-folder 18: 24)
  - American Committee for the Preservation of Abu Simbel, 1964 (Box-folder 18: 25)
  - American Council for Judaism, 1947-1966 (Box-folder 18: 26)
  - American Enterprise Institute, 1971-1978 (Box-folder 18: 27)
  - American Friends of the Middle East, 1954-1970 (Box-folder 18: 28)
  - American Independent Oil Company, 1956-1961 (Box-folder 18: 29)
  - American International Oil Company, 1964 (Box-folder 18: 30)
  - American Jewish Alternatives to Zionism, 1969-1979 (Box-folder 18: 31)
  - American Psychiatric Association, 1976 (Box-folder 18: 32)
  - American University of Beirut, 1957-1970 (Box-folder 18: 33)
  - Americans for Justice in the Middle East, 1969-1981 (Box-folder 18: 34)
  - Americans for Middle East Understanding, 1978 (Box-folder 18: 35)
  - Anaf Foundation, 1970-1971 (Box-folder 18: 36)
  - Anber, Fred G., 1969-1970 (Box-folder 18: 37)
  - Anderson, Francis W., 1948-1949 (Box-folder 18: 38)
  - Anglo-Arab Association, 1966 (Box-folder 18: 39)
  - Anti-Defamation League of B'nai B'rith, 1949-1952 (Box-folder 18: 40)
  - Anti-Zionist Committee of Soviet Public Opinion, 1983-1984 (Box-folder 18: 41)
  - Antiochian Orthodox Christian Archdiocese, 1969-1980 (Box-folder 18: 42)
  - Antone, K. E., 1970 (Box-folder 18: 43)
  - AP to AP (Arab People to American People) TV, 1982 (Box-folder 18: 44)
  - Apostolic Nunciature, United States of America, 1987 (Box-folder 18: 45)
  - Arab-American Dialogue Committee, 1978-1979 (Box-folder 18: 46)
  - Arab-American Friendship, 1979 (Box-folder 18: 47)
  - Arab British Centre, 1977 (Box-folder 18: 48)
  - Arab Information Center, 1970-1979 (Box-folder 18: 49)
  - Arab News, 1978-1980 (Box-folder 18: 50)
  - Arabian American Oil Company, 1956-1984 (Box-folder 18: 51)
  - Arafat, Yasir, 1969-1991 (Box-folder 18: 52)
  - Arizona Daily Star, 1958-1960 (Box-folder 18: 53)
  - Arthur, Paul, 1960 (Box-folder 18: 54)
  - ASKME, 1970 (Box-folder 18: 55)
  - Assad, Hafez, 1975-1991 (Box-folder 18: 56)
  - Association of Arab-American University Graduates, 1968-1982 (Box-folder 18: 57)
  - Association parlementaire pour la coopiration euro-arabe, 1984-1985 (Box-folder 18: 58)
  - Atlantic Richfield Foundation, 1973 (Box-folder 18: 59)
  - Attwood, William ( Look), 1967 (Box-folder 18: 60)
  - Augustinian Historical Institute, 1979 (Box-folder 18: 61)
  - Australian League of Rights, 1979-1980 (Box-folder 18: 62)
  - Austria. Permanent Mission to the United Nations, 1981 (Box-folder 18: 63)
  - Avnery, Uri, 1964-1965 (Box-folder 18: 64)
  - Azkoul, William N., 1978 (Box-folder 18: 65)
  - Azzam, Abdul Rahman, 1966 (Box-folder 18: 66)
  - Baghdad Observer, 1980 (Box-folder 19: 1)
  - Bahrain. Ministry of Information, 1974-1983 (Box-folder 19: 2)
  - Bahrain. Permanent Mission to the United Nations, 1980 (Box-folder 19: 3)
  - Baker, Harold D., 1977-1979 (Box-folder 19: 4)
  - Baker, James A., III, 1992-1994 (Box-folder 153: 16)
  - Baldwin, Donald, 1968-1985 (Box-folder 19: 5)
  - Baldwin, Hanson W., 1956 (Box-folder 19: 6)
  - Balfour, Lord, 1960 (Box-folder 19: 7)
  - Balfrey, Thomas F., 1983 (Box-folder 19: 8)
  - Ball, Douglas B., 1994 (Box-folder 153: 17)
  - Ball, George W., 1985-1992 (Box-folder 19: 9)
  - Bancroft, Harding, 1966-1977 (Box-folder 19: 10)
  - Barakat, Joseph, 1968 (Box-folder 19: 11)
  - Barbanel, Howard Stephen, 1972 (Box-folder 19: 12)
  - Barnes, Harry Elmer, 1965 (Box-folder 19: 13)
  - Baroody, Mrs. Jamil, 1979 (Box-folder 19: 14)
  - Baruch, Bernard M., 1954 (Box-folder 19: 15)
  - Baton, Virginia, 1957 (Box-folder 19: 16)
  - Bazzaz, Abdel Rahman al-, 1966 (Box-folder 19: 17)
  - Beate Klarsfeld Foundation, 1982 (Box-folder 19: 18)
  - Beatley, Charles E., 1982 (Box-folder 19: 19)
  - Beautiful People Publishers, 1980 (Box-folder 19: 20)
  - Beer, Ethel S., 1965 (Box-folder 19: 21)
  - Begin, Menachem, 1978-1980 (Box-folder 19: 22)
  - Begum, Paul G., n.d. (Box-folder 19: 23)
  - Bellmon, Henry, 1970-1971 (Box-folder 19: 24)
  - Benoist, Alain de, 1980 (Box-folder 19: 25)
  - Berger, Elmer [See also: American Council for Judaism and American Jewish Alternatives to Zionism], 1979 (Box-folder 19: 26)
  - Berger, Morroe, 1957 (Box-folder 19: 27)
  - Berlin, Michael J., 1981 (Box-folder 19: 28)
  - Bernazani, Paul J., 1977-1981 (Box-folder 19: 29)
  - Bevin, Ernest, 1947 (Box-folder 19: 30)
  - Bogardus, George F., 1979 (Box-folder 19: 31)
  - Bolt, Robert, 1963 (Box-folder 19: 32)
  - Bonar, John and Roxanne, 1975 (Box-folder 19: 33)
  - Booth, John Nicholls, 1967-1982 (Box-folder 19: 34)
  - Booth, Newell S., Jr., 1968 (Box-folder 19: 35)
  - Bosco, Philip, 1982 (Box-folder 19: 36)
  - Bourguiba, Habib, Jr., 1964-1969 (Box-folder 19: 37)
  - Boutros, Eli, 1969 (Box-folder 19: 38)
  - Brady, Lawrence J., 1982 (Box-folder 19: 39)
  - Breslin, Jimmy, 1978 (Box-folder 19: 40)
  - British Anti-Zionist Organization, Palestine Solidarity, 1979-1982 (Box-folder 19: 41)
  - British Broadcasting Corporation, 1980 (Box-folder 19: 42)
  - British League of Rights, 1981 (Box-folder 19: 43)
  - Brizendine, Richard, 1979-1983 (Box-folder 19: 44)
  - Broadcast Interview Connection, 1981-1982 (Box-folder 19: 45)
  - Brossard, Stratford, 1976 (Box-folder 19: 46)
  - Brown, George S., 1974 (Box-folder 19: 47)
  - Brown, L. Dean, 1978-1981 (Box-folder 19: 48)
  - Brown, Philip, 1957 (Box-folder 19: 49)
  - Brownfeld, Allan C., 1957-1984 (Box-folder 19: 50)
  - Brzezinski, Zbigniew, 1983 (Box-folder 19: 51)
  - Bucci, Maurizio, 1976 (Box-folder 19: 52)
  - Buchanan, Patrick J., 1978-1988 (Box-folder 19: 53)
  - Buck, Pitman, Jr., 1977-1982 (Box-folder 19: 54)
  - Buckley, William F., Jr., 1957-1986 (Box-folder 19: 55)
  - Bull, Odd, 1977 (Box-folder 19: 56)
  - Burleson, O, mar, 1962-1978 (Box-folder 19: 57)
  - Burns, Alice, 1956-1968 (Box-folder 19: 58)
  - Bush, George H., 1978-1992 (Box-folder 19: 59)
  - Bushnaq, Abdul, 1970-1980 (Box-folder 19: 60)
  - Bustani, Emile, 1961 (Box-folder 19: 61)
  - Butros, Antoine E. [See: Institute for Palestine Studies; and Tamari, Ludwig W. and Joseph]
  - Byrd, Harry F., Jr., 1955 (Box-folder 19: 62)
  - Caldwell, Taylor, 1971 (Box-folder 19: 63)
  - California Texas Oil, 1956-1957 (Box-folder 19: 64)
  - Canada-Palestine Association, 1979 (Box-folder 19: 65)
  - Canadian Arab Friendship League, 1963 (Box-folder 19: 66)
  - Canadian Arab Friendship Society of Toronto, 1965-1966 (Box-folder 19: 67)
  - Canadians for Justice in the Middle East, 1982 (Box-folder 19: 68)
  - Canadians for Peace in the Middle East, 1983 (Box-folder 19: 69)
  - Capell, Frank, 1971 (Box-folder 19: 70)
  - Capital Speakers, 1985 (Box-folder 19: 71)
  - Carleton, Alford, 1958 (Box-folder 19: 72)
  - Carmichael, Kenn and Sue, 1967 (Box-folder 19: 73)
  - Carter, Jimmy, 1978-1985 (Box-folder 19: 74)
  - Carvely, Andrew, 1969 (Box-folder 19: 75)
  - Cavett, Dick, 1972-1977 (Box-folder 19: 76)
  - Centro-Cultural Cubano-Arabe, 1971 (Box-folder 19: 77)
  - Chaplin, G. G., 1970 (Box-folder 19: 78)
  - Chicago Daily News, 1959-1960 (Box-folder 19: 79)
  - Childs, J. Rives, 1977-1979 (Box-folder 19: 80)
  - Chisholm, A. H. T., 1960 (Box-folder 19: 81)
  - Chomsky, Noam, 1978-1984 (Box-folder 19: 82)
  - Christian Science Monitor, 1978 (Box-folder 20: 1)
  - Christopher, Warren, 1994 (Box-folder 153: 18)
  - Church, Frank, 1979 (Box-folder 20: 2)
  - Clark, Gerald, 1969 (Box-folder 20: 3)
  - Clark, William P., 1982-1984 (Box-folder 20: 4)
  - Cleveland, Ray L., 1968-1983 (Box-folder 20: 5)
  - Clinton, Bill [See also: SPEECHES AND WRITINGS, 6/95], 1992 (Box-folder 152: 56)
  - Coates, David, 1989 (Box-folder 152: 24)
  - Coe, Richard, 1971 (Box-folder 20: 6)
  - Collins, John P. [See also: SUBJECT FILE, Virgin Islands. Water and Power Authority], undated (Box-folder 20: 7)
  - Columbia Broadcasting System, 1952-1985 (Box-folder 20: 8)
  - Columbia Forum, 1970 (Box-folder 20: 9)
  - Columbia School of Journalism, 1981 (Box-folder 20: 10)
  - Committee for the Single Six-Year Presidential Term, 1983 (Box-folder 20: 11)
  - Committee on Truth in the Middle East, 1978 (Box-folder 20: 12)
  - Committee to Support Middle East Liberation, 1971 (Box-folder 20: 13)
  - Common Cause, 1974 (Box-folder 20: 14)
  - Congressional Record, 1970-1971 (Box-folder 20: 15)
  - Connolly, Joseph V., 1957 (Box-folder 20: 16)
  - Connors, Michael F., 1966-1969 (Box-folder 20: 17)
  - Conservative Book Club, 1965 (Box-folder 20: 18)
  - Continental Oil Co., 1976-1983 (Box-folder 20: 19)
  - Cooper, Edward A., 1959 (Box-folder 20: 20)
  - Cooper, John M., 1960 (Box-folder 20: 21)
  - Cooper, John S., 1971-1972 (Box-folder 20: 22)
  - Cornell Alumni News, 1965 (Box-folder 20: 23)
  - Cornell Daily Sun, 1955 (Box-folder 20: 24)
  - Cornell University, 1979 (Box-folder 20: 25)
  - Cosmopolitan Magazine, 1954 (Box-folder 20: 26)
  - Costello, Clement, 1982 (Box-folder 20: 27)
  - Cottam, Howard R., 1965-1978 (Box-folder 20: 28)
  - Cotten, Richard B., 1970 (Box-folder 20: 29)
  - Council for the Advancement of Arab-British Understanding, 1970-1980 (Box-folder 20: 30)
  - Cousins, Norman, 1965-1973 (Box-folder 20: 31)
  - Crane, Philip M., 1978 (Box-folder 20: 32)
  - Cranston, Alan, 1983-1984 (Box-folder 20: 33)
  - Crider, John H., 1963 (Box-folder 20: 34)
  - Crystal, John C., 1966 (Box-folder 20: 35)
  - Curry, W. A., 1981 (Box-folder 20: 36)
  - Czechoslovakia. Mission to the United Nations, 1980-1981 (Box-folder 20: 37)
  - D'Amato, Alfonso M., 1980-1983 (Box-folder 20: 38)
  - D'Amours, Norman E., 1981 (Box-folder 20: 39)
  - Dacey, Norman F., 1972-1985 (Box-folder 20: 40)
  - Daily Pantagraph (Bloomington), 1960 (Box-folder 20: 41)
  - Dajani, Ali, 1969 (Box-folder 20: 42)
  - Dajani, Burhan, 1981 (Box-folder 20: 43)
  - Dallas Morning News, 1959 (Box-folder 20: 44)
  - Dattelbaum, David, 1987 (Box-folder 152: 43)
  - Daoud, Mohammed, 1970 (Box-folder 20: 45)
  - Davis, John H., 1964 (Box-folder 20: 46)
  - De Courcy, John, 1982 (Box-folder 20: 47)
  - Delaney, Edward L., 1965-1968 (Box-folder 20: 48)
  - Denton, Charles R., 1980-1982 (Box-folder 20: 49)
  - Denton, Jeremiah, 1981-1982 (Box-folder 20: 50)
  - Diab, Jamil, 1969-1979 (Box-folder 20: 51)
  - Dole, Elizabeth H., 1984 (Box-folder 20: 52)
  - Dole, Robert, 1987 (Box-folder 20: 53)
  - Donaldson, Sam, 1987 (Box-folder 20: 54)
  - Dorney, Cathryn, 1973-1974 (Box-folder 20: 55)
  - Douglass, Paul, 1981 (Box-folder 20: 56)
  - Du Brul, George, 1978-1979 (Box-folder 20: 57)
  - Eaks, Louis, 1973-1979 (Box-folder 20: 58)
  - East, John P., 1981 (Box-folder 20: 59)
  - East-West Foundation, 1979 (Box-folder 20: 60)
  - Eaton, Charles A., 1948 (Box-folder 20: 61)
  - Ecevit, Bulent, 1979 (Box-folder 20: 62)
  - Economic Club of New York, 1981 (Box-folder 20: 63)
  - Eddy, William A., 1950 (Box-folder 20: 64)
  - Egolf, James E., 1979-1981 (Box-folder 20: 65)
  - Egypt. Consulate (New York), 1960-1979 (Box-folder 21: 1)
  - Egypt. Consulate (San Francisco), 1957 (Box-folder 21: 2)
  - Egypt. Embassy (Great Britain), 1969 (Box-folder 21: 3)
  - Egypt. Embassy (United States), 1975-1985 (Box-folder 21: 4)
  - Egypt. Ministry of Economy and Foreign Trade, 1969 (Box-folder 21: 5)
  - Egypt. Ministry of Foreign Affairs, 1981 (Box-folder 21: 6)
  - Egypt. Ministry of Information, 1960-1968 (Box-folder 21: 7)
  - Egypt. Ministry of National Guidance and Culture, 1967 (Box-folder 21: 8)
  - Egypt. Ministry of Petroleum, 1974-1975 (Box-folder 21: 9)
  - Egypt. Office of the President, 1959-1969 (Box-folder 21: 10)
  - Egypt. People's Assembly, 1975-1980 (Box-folder 21: 11)
  - Egypt. Permanent Mission to the United Nations, 1969-1985 (Box-folder 21: 12)
  - Egypt. State Information Service, 1982 (Box-folder 21: 13)
  - Egypt. Tourist Office, 1958-1961 (Box-folder 21: 14)
  - Eichler, Franklin C., 1971 (Box-folder 21: 15)
  - Eilts, Hermann Frederick, 1975-1985 (Box-folder 21: 16)
  - Eisenhower, Dwight D., 1962-1967 (Box-folder 21: 17)
  - Eisenhower, Mamie Doud, 1969-1971 (Box-folder 21: 18)
  - Elias, Gertrude, 1964-1965 (Box-folder 21: 19)
  - Ellender, Allen J., 1957-1971 (Box-folder 21: 20)
  - Emmons, Frederick E., 1965 (Box-folder 21: 21)
  - Epp, Frank H., 1969 (Box-folder 21: 22)
  - Ernst, Morris L., See also St. Martin's Press, 1952. (Box-folder 21: 23)
  - Esquire, 1967-1968 (Box-folder 21: 24)
  - Estes, Carol K., 1981-1983 (Box-folder 21: 25)
  - Ethridge, Willie Snow, 1949-1950 (Box-folder 21: 26)
  - European Coordinating Committee of Friendship Societies with the Arab World, 1981 (Box-folder 21: 27)
  - EXXON, 1975-1983 (Box-folder 21: 28)
  - Fahd ibn 'Abd al-'Aziz, King of Saudi Arabia, 1985 (Box-folder 21: 29)
  - Fahmy, Awatef, 1960-1961 (Box-folder 21: 30)
  - Fahmy, Mostafa Hussein, 1961-1964 (Box-folder 21: 31)
  - Faisal, King of Saudi Arabia, 1974 (Box-folder 21: 32)
  - Faisal, Mohammed al-, 1975 (Box-folder 21: 33)
  - Fakhro, Ali, 1979-1983 (Box-folder 21: 34)
  - Farber, Barry, 1979 (Box-folder 21: 35)
  - Fateh, 1970 (Box-folder 21: 36)
  - Fauntroy, Walter E., 1984 (Box-folder 21: 37)
  - Faurisson, Robert, 1982 (Box-folder 21: 38)
  - Federal Communications Commission, 1968-1982 (Box-folder 21: 39)
  - Federation of American-Arab Organizations, 1968-1977 (Box-folder 21: 40)
  - Feisal, Abdul Aziz Masaad, 1968 (Box-folder 21: 41)
  - Fennekohl, Arthur C., 1967 (Box-folder 21: 42)
  - Findley, Paul, 1978-1979 (Box-folder 21: 43)
  - Finletter, Thomas, 1950 (Box-folder 21: 44)
  - Fisk, Fred, 1986 (Box-folder 21: 45)
  - Flynn, Patrick F., 1980-1982 (Box-folder 21: 46)
  - Forbes, Edith E., 1966-1967 (Box-folder 21: 47)
  - Fordham University, 1943 (Box-folder 21: 48)
  - Foss, Joe, 1978 (Box-folder 21: 49)
  - Foundation for Christian Theology, 1975 (Box-folder 21: 50)
  - Frame, Flora, 1960-1963 (Box-folder 21: 51)
  - Fraser, Alexander, 1958 (Box-folder 21: 52)
  - Friends of Palestine (Martin Zammit), 1989 (Box-folder 152: 44)
  - Frost, David, 1970-1971 (Box-folder 21: 53)
  - Fry, Ian R., 1981 (Box-folder 21: 54)
  - Fulbright, J. William, 1971-1983 (Box-folder 21: 55)
  - Gagen, Wilfred, 1963-1964 (Box-folder 21: 56)
  - Galbraith, Evan G., 1981 (Box-folder 21: 57)
  - Garrity, Devin A., 1965-1978 (Box-folder 21: 58)
  - GEM Publications, 1981 (Box-folder 21: 59)
  - General Union of Chambers of Commerce, Industry and Agriculture for Arab Countries, 1970 (Box-folder 21: 60)
  - Gerstenfeld, Norman, 1949 (Box-folder 21: 61)
  - Getty, J. P., 1956 (Box-folder 21: 62)
  - Ghandour, Ali, 1980 (Box-folder 21: 63)
  - Ghilan, Maxim, 1970-1981 (Box-folder 21: 64)